Street Guides
Street Guides
1852-1954
1905-1954
Mss.arc
New York Academy of Medicine Library. Rare Book Room.
Historical Statement
Street and city guides were distributed by doctors as a means to advertise their medical services. Many of the practices specialized in men's health and sexually transmitted disesases.
Scope and Content
Most of the pamphlets are as much about health and medical services as street listings. Some include other local information such as railroad fares, building guides, and calendars or baseball schedules (used to estimate publication dates).
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The New York Academy of Medicine Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Streets -- Illinois -- Chicago -- Guidebooks; New York (N.Y.) -- Guidebooks; Streets -- Colorado -- Denver -- Guidebooks; Streets -- Missouri -- Saint Louis -- Guidebooks; Streets -- Ohio -- Youngstown -- Guidebooks; Streets -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- Guidebooks; Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Guidebooks; Transportation -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- Guidebooks; Sexually transmitted dieseases -- therapy -- advertisements; Sexually transmitted diseases -- treatment -- advertisements; Books printed as advertisements
Container List
- Street Guides
  - Chicago
    - City Health Institute. New Chicago street guide., Undated (Box 1)
    - Chicago Health Institute. New Chicago street guide., [1932?] (Box 1)
    - Chicago Medical Institute. The latest Chicago street guide and other useful information., [1938?]; [1940?], c1939; c1942; 3 items. (Box 1)
    - Chicago Medical Institute. The latest Chicago street guide surface lines and other useful information., [1941?], c1939 (Box 1)
    - Culp, E.E. The latest Chicago street guide and other useful information., [1945?], c1944 (Box 1)
    - Dearborn Health Service. The latest Chicago street guide., [1950?], c1949 (Box 1)
    - Illinois Health Institute. Latest Chicago street guide., [1940?] (Box 1)
    - Illinois Health Institute. Latest social security and street guide., [1938?] (Box 1)
    - Illinois Health Institute. Up-to-date Chicago street guide and baseball schedules., [1936?] (Box 1)
    - Mabee, J.R. Chicago street guide., [1931?], c1929 (Box 1)
    - Mabee, J.R. New Chicago street guide., [1924?] (Box 1)
    - Riley, John M. The latest Chicago street guide and other useful information., [1948?], c1944; [1950?], c1944; [1954?], c1944; 3 items. (Box 1)
    - Thompson, E.G. Latest Chicago street guide., [1951?]; 2 copies. (Box 1)
  - Denver
    - Denver Medical Dispensary Co. Denver street guide and directory. Denver Print and Pub Co., [1907?] (Box 1)
    - Denver Medical Institute. Pocket guide to the city of Denver. The Midwest Printing Co., Undated. (Box 1)
  - New York
    - Phelps' New York City guide. New York: T.C. Fanning, 1852 (Box 1)
    - Union Medical Council. U.M.C., [1906?], c1905 (Box 1)
  - Philadelphia
    - Ferry, C.T. Philadelphia: trolley, motor bus, street, health, and latest social security guide., [1938?] (Box 1)
    - Treible, S. Decker. A pocket note book., [1910?] (Box 1)
    - Dr. Shearer and Associates. A Book of Information: Parks, Museums, Libraries, and Scientific Institutions., Undated. (Box 1)
  - St. Louis
    - Central Medical Office. St. Louis street and health guide., [1948?], [1954?], [1954?]; 3 items. (Box 1)
    - National Medical Institute. Street guide of the city of St. Louis., Undated. (Box 1)
  - Youngstown, OH
    - Dr. McClelland and Associates. Latest Youngstown street guide and surburban auto routes., c1941 (Box 1)
Provenance
Gift of William Helfand, 2005.